<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Q100 on Erin&#39;s Audio Corner</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/q100/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Q100 on Erin&#39;s Audio Corner</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/q100/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Kef Q100 Speaker Drive Unit Testing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/driveunits/kef-q100-drive-unit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/driveunits/kef-q100-drive-unit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;iframe src=&#34;//rcm-na.amazon-adsystem.com/e/cm?o=1&amp;p=48&amp;l=ur1&amp;category=amazonhomepage&amp;f=ifr&amp;linkID=45d00811e11005f66cf1dcae88dc3060&amp;t=medlemusin-20&amp;tracking_id=medlemusin-20&#34; width=&#34;728&#34; height=&#34;90&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; marginwidth=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;border:none;&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;br clear=&#34;all&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;br&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As with the &lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;Kef HTS3001SE I tested&lt;/a&gt;, I ordered a set of the Kef Q100 Bookshelf speakers in order to remove and review the raw Q100 driver itself.  I really wanted to see how this coaxial design performed.  Zaph had already tested this one but I wanted to do Klippel LSI testing on it to see how the suspension performed.  He actually mentioned this in his writeup and I thought it would be cool to provide the results.  Of course, since I had it on the test baffle I did some other standard measurements as well.  The one I was interested in, but didn’t perform on the HTS3001SE driver was tweeter frequency response performance with movement of the woofer.  I don’t necessarily have an easy way to test this so I did something a bit different: I used a 9v battery to statically ‘fix’ the woofer either in the coil out or coil in position and measured the response.  I then compared this to the woofer at rest performance of the tweeter and did a direct comparison.  This is discussed further below.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
